NEEL SHAH

Thunder Bay, ON neelknightme@gmail.com https://neelshah18.github.io

QUALIFICATION SUMMARY

Interdisciplinary research experience in food consumption change and data sciences work with several professional institutions. Knowledge in data analysis, machine learning, programming languages and applications for scientific programming and large scale system designing obtained through both academic and extracurricular pursuits. Background in teaching rudimentary concepts gained through research assistantship and summer activities.

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistance: datalab.science, Thunder Bay

November 2017 - Present

- Develop "Elasticsearch" on distributed server(20+ nodes) which handle query on 1TB within 1 min.
- Working on Twitter data analysis project for health informatics.

Machine Learning Engineer: Datalog.ai, California

January 2017 - August 2017

- Developed NER functionality using NLP and without NLP with 90%+ efficiency.
- Create back-end data analysis system for text analysis
- Developed API which can handle million requests per second.
- Managed Nosql and SQL database and optimization of it.

Data Analysis Intern: Panchamrut Dairy, Godhra

July 2016 - December 2016

- Developed real time data analysis system which can handle 5 GB/Second.
- Forecast sales pattern with 71% efficiency.
- Analyzed current spending data and help to reduce cost up to 2%.

Open Source: GitHub

April 2016 - Present

- An official writer of "emot" python library.
- contributor to official Python "emoji" library
- "Research trend of AI in India" data analysis project under Malaikannan Sankarasubbu VP of Saama tech.,Inc., Dr. Jacob Minz R&D Manager of Synopsys India, Anirban Santara Google Ph.D. fellow.

EDUCATION

Master in Computer Science: Lakehead University, Thunder Bay

September 2017 - Present

- Working on data analysis model based on social data to understand human caloric consumption and caloric burning and it's trend in Canada.
- Score 91.5% average.

Master in Information Technology: PIET, Vadodara

July 2014 - June 2016

Thesis: Searching on encrypted data:

- Research shows solution for privacy and confidentiality of data in cloud/server about user sensitive data with IND-CKA2 security.
- Score 8.78 GPA based on 10 scale.

Bachelor in Computer Science & engg.: PIET, Vadodara

July 2010 - June 2014

Project: E-money for Hyper mall with RFID and Fingerprint security:

• Successful completion of this project will make the use of paper money obsolete. Customer will have the advantage of using this system with enhanced security and flexibility.

SKILLS

- Language: Python, Java, R and C
- Database: MongoDB, Elasticsearch, MySQL, Redis
- Medium to large scale data analysis system development through.
- API development cycle and maintaining
- Generating reports and visualization of analysis results

AWARDS

- 8000\$/Yearly RA Scholarship.
- 1st Rank in 2nd sem in Master in Technology
- 2nd Rank in 3rd sem in Master in Technology
- 2nd Rank in 4th sem in Master in Technology

CERTIFICATES

- Research management Graduate Professional Skills, Ontario
- Mentoring Undergraduate student- Graduate Professional Skills, Ontario
- Intellectual Competency Graduate Professional Skills, Ontario